Govardhan Srinivas

Software Development Engineer III

(+31) 634412970

govardhan.s92@gmail.com

Skills Synopsis

Technical Skills: Angular, React, Spring, Express, Bootstrap, Typescript, MEAN Stack, MongoDB, SQL, HTML, CSS,

SASS, Git, Jenkins, Docker, Shell scripts

Industries: IT Consulting, Healthcare

Experience Summary

I'm a creative professional Full Stack Web Developer with over 6 years of experience in latest web design and development technologies.

I have good exposure in developing single page applications, portals, hybrid apps, native apps, CRM platforms along with strong understanding of best practices, analytical capabilities, organisational skills and ability to complete a successful implementation.

Professional Experience

Dutchview IT, Netherlands

Jan 2018 – Present

SDE III

FlexWhere - It's a software product for enabling organisations with **hybrid working** and **hot desking** solutions with reservation for workplaces, meeting rooms and parking spots, realtime and history statistics and more.

- Was an integral part in design, development and deployment phases of the product development lifecycle.
- Worked on critical features of web apps Real-time data sync, Chat app, Analytics, Performance etc.
- Develop REST services for complex calculations, web sockets and chat applications.
- Develop Angular and React solutions with authentication, authorisation, routing, templates, directives, services, filters and custom solutions to meet requirements and optimise the performance.
- Validating user actions on the client side and providing responsive feedback.
- Test Driven Development with Jasmine and Jest.
- Automate, Optimise the development process with webpack, jenkins along with CI and CD

Cognizant Technology Solutions, Bangalore

Apr 2016 – Dec 2017

Full Stack Web developer

Microsoft BVS App – Microsoft BVS(Business Value Service) App is a MICROSOFT product which predicts the future profit or loss of a digital initiative provided initial capital, costs and benefits data.

Implementation strategy: Angular 4, Typescript 2.4, Node, Express, Webpack, HTML, CSS, VS Code

- Agile implementation for solution development and VSO for project management.
- Develop Node based REST API services and Angular client solution with authentication, authorisation, routing, templates, directives, services, filters and responsive app according to project requirement.
- Develop customer dashboard with overall productivity of the app with highcharts.

Cloud Central Integration – Cloud Central Integration (CCI) is an integration platform, which is used to integrate customer's cloud and on-premises applications. Product itself is a cloud offering and customer's integrations are performed on a subscription basis.

Implementation strategy: Angular 2, Typescript, AngularJS 1.6.x, Java, Bower, Grunt, Node, HTML, CSS, SVN, Sublime

- Spiral Model implementation for solution development.
- Develop Java based REST services comprising PL/SQL as a database.
- Develop Angular solution with authentication, authorisation, routing, templates, directives, services, filters and responsive app according to project requirement. Automate, Optimise the development process with Bower, Grunt and Node.

KBI Integration – KBI Integration is a scheduler application. My role was to enhance the application to native android apps using the webview concept of Cordova.

Implementation strategy: Cordova, jQuery UI, SVN, Sublime etc.

- Enhance the existing app to support mobile platforms.
- Develop an android app using Cordova platform.
- Test overall functionality of the app.

Indegene Lifesystems Pvt Ltd., Bangalore

May 2015 – Apr 2016

Web Developer

Interactive Detailers – Interactive Detailers (iDetail) apps are FDA approved, that help Medical reps connect doctors to market their brands. My role is to develop CLM (Closed Loop Marketing) hybrid apps for iOS devices using platforms like Veeva CRM (Customer Relationship Management), Salesforce and more.

Implementation strategy: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Veeva CRM, Veeva analytics, Salesforce, SVN, Sublime etc.

- Interaction with the client and gather requirements.
- Develop user Veeva app compatible rich UI for iOS devices like Mac and iPads.
- Agile Model implementation for solution development
- Capture analytics like user clicks, time spent, user interests etc.,
- Cross Browser compatibility testing.

Interactive Native App – This app is FDA approved, that helps Medical reps connect doctors to market their brands. My role is to develop native apps for iOS devices using platforms like Xcode, Salesforce and more.

Implementation strategy: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Xcode, analytics, Salesforce, SVN, Sublime etc.

- Interaction with the client and gather requirements.
- Develop Native apps compatible for iOS devices like Mac and iPads.
- Capture analytics like user clicks, time spent, user interests etc.,
- Cross Browser compatibility testing.

Publications

Title	Degree
TICC	Degree

Portfolio https://govardhan-srinivas.github.io/

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/govardhan-srinivas

Blog https://medium.com/@govardhan.s

Excel NPV https://www.npmjs.com/package/excel-npv

Custom select dropdown https://www.npmjs.com/package/custom-select-dropdown

Awards

Title Degree

Best Performer of the month Indegene Lifesystems

Aspire Double Up Award Cognizant
Wah Points, Brownie Points Cognizant

Certifications

Institution Degree

NIIT, Bangalore Bachelor of Engineering
Code School Real Time web with Node
Cognizant Frontend developer
Cognizant Full stack web developer

Education

Institution Degree

Visvesvaraya Technological University

Sarvodaya Pre-university College, Tumkur

B. G National Public School, Bangalore

XII

X